NASIRUDEEN BALIKIS OMOTUNRAYO | FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

- @ omolewabalikis149@gmail.com
- 08085754756
- 22 Ashimowu Bakare Street Itire Surulere Lagos
- balikis-omolewa-portfolio.vercel.app
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/balikis-omolewa-78632b221
- https://twitter.com/OmolewaBalikis

Objective

Frontend Web Developer with proven experience in creating and maintaining codebase for reusability. Passionate about learning and development with a desire to apply skills to build and maintain functional, attractive and responsive websites. Well-versed in numerous programming languages JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, PHP, SQL, Graphics, WordPress, SEO, GIT

Experience

Bigfix Integrated Technologies

2023 - Present

Frontend Web Developer | WordPress Expert | SEO Executive

- · Maintained the functionality of existing website
- · Provided support to Clients existing website
- Build an attractive and responsive landing page website for lead conversion
- · Build an interactive Blog page website for brand visibility.
- Revamp an existing website to optimize website pages to drive more traffic to site.

Bigfix Integrated Technologies (NYSC)

2022 - 2023

Frontend Web Developer | SEO Executive | WordPress Expert

- · Build responsive website that are mobile friendly
- Design fully responsive website with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap5 from start to finish
- Create an E-commerce website for online shopping using WordPress
- Build beautiful and interactive website for clients without compromising the functionality.
- Ensure high quality graphics standards and brand consistency.
- Organic Search Engine Optimization to increase the website traffic.
- · Optimized user experienced
- · Uses HTML, JavaScript and Css to bring concepts to life
- · Uses PHP, MySQL, SQL languages to send information (Data) to database and to mail address
- Develop and maintain the user interface
- · Maintain and improve existing website
- · Worked closely with senior developers to broaden my knowledge in the field.
- · Support and solve problems of clients existing website.

Bigfix Integrated Technologies(Intern)

2018 - 2019

Frontend Developer | Graphics Designer (Interns)

- · Build website's with different template
- Experienced work with team to build small accounting software
- Use markup languages like html, css, JavaScript to create user-friendly web pages.
- · Uses PHP, MySQL, SQL languages to send information (Data) to database and to mail address.
- · Maintain and improve website optimization applications for maximum speed.
- · Ensure high quality graphic standards and brand consistency.
- · Worked closely with senior developers to broaden my knowledge in JavaScript.
- · Build reusable codes.





Education

Gateway ICT polytechnic Saapade

2016 - 2021

Computer Science (HND)

T

Certification

Higher National Diploma (Computer Science) 2021

National Youth Service

Modern React and Redux 2022

Advanced React and Redux 2022

Web Development2023

(Legacy) JTS

Transition from Junior Developer to Senior Developer 2023



Projects

Online E-commerce Website:

Justhalal Online Shopping

Build a dynamic functioning e-commerce website, fully responsive and mobile friendly with (Paystack Payment Integration) for easy payment from the site.

Link: www.justhalal.com

Job Placement Website:

Placement-Hub

Build a colorful stunning website with interactive user interface, responsive and mobile friendly on all browsers. Design a application form to collect user information and apply online through the site.

Link: www.placement-hub.com

Job Recruitment Website:

Jobfinder

Designed a dynamic functioning landing page website, stunning and interactive for job recruitment for employers.

Link: www.placement.com/jobfinder

Workspace & Event Center Website:

HmvPlace

Build a responsive functioning workspace website using Bootstrap5 with PHP to submit data to (MYSQL database) and email address.

Link: www.hmvtravels.com/hmv-place

Organic Search Optimization(SEO):

FastraSuite Website

Generate traffic to the website using on-page SEO, off-page SEO, and Ads campaign.

Link to site: www.fastrasuite.com



Skills

Critical thinking



Problem solving



• Ability to work with or without supervision



· Ability to work as part of team or individually



• Familiarity with browser testing and debugging



• Knowledge of SEO principles



Hobbies

- Praying
- Reading
- Internet surfing
- Learning new thing
- Writing